Guide to the Taylor Wine Company records, 1950-1989.
Taylor Wine Company records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Taylor Wine Company records, 1950-1989.
6718
Taylor Wine Company.
4.1 cubic feet.
Correspondence, business and accounting records, photographs, newspaper clippings, audio recordings, and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, business and accounting records relating the the operation of the Taylor Wine Company in Hammondsport, N.Y. Letters, notes, and statistics in wine advertising for and by Taylor Wine Company and D'Arcy Advertising Company.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, business and accounting records relating the the operation of the Taylor Wine Company in Hammondsport. Letters, notes, and statistics in wine advertising for and by Taylor Wine Company and D'Arcy Advertising Company. Also included are magazine clippings, newspapers, photos, negatives, audio recordings, articles, meeting reports, school coursework and publications. The collection shows the success of the company through smart and extensive marketing. Notable figures in this collection are Walter S. Taylor, Grayton H. Taylor, and William L. Rech.
Also included in this collection are Taylor family photographs, personal correspondence and school papers written by Walter Taylor, along with a set of autographed prints by H. Hawkins of early aviation.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Taylor Wine Company.; Taylor, Clarence W.; Taylor, Fred C.; Taylor, Greyton H.; Taylor, Walter S.; Taylor Wine Company.
Subjects:
Viticulture.; Wine and wine making.; Wineries -- New York (State) -- Hammondsport.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
RELATED MATERIALS
‡3 See also the Greyton H. Taylor Wine Museum at Bully Hill Vineyards in Hammondsport, N.Y. for additional archival material and photographs of the Taylor Wine Company and Taylor family.
CONTAINER LIST
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, January 1961, Jan 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Gordon E. Hyde, letters, magazine clippings, advertisement plans, receipts
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Feb 1961, February 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Gordon E. Hyde, letters, publications, magazine clippings, receipts
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Mar 1961, March 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Gordon E. Hyde, Walter S. Taylor, recipes, statistical data, letters, receipts, magazine clippings, advertisements
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, April 1961, April 1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Gordon E. Hyde, letters, advertisements, articles
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, May 1961, May 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Gordon E. Hyde, letters, news clippings, market statistics
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, June 1961, June 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Gordon E. Hyde, letters, photos, news clippings, articles, advertisements
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company 1961, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, letters, news clippings, articles, advertisements
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Aug 1961, August 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, letters, news clippings, articles, advertisements, the Taylor Wine Check-Booster Plan
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Sept 1961, September 1961 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Walter S. Taylor, Greyton H. Taylor, William L. Rech, Lucille Shearwood, letters, news clippings, articles, advertisements
- Merchandising of Advertising 1961, part 1, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Magazines: Esquire, Bride's, Holiday, Cosmopolitan, Newsweek, Time, Living, Bakersfield Californian, True, Redbook; William L. Rech, letters
- Merchandising of Advertising 1961, part 2, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Magazine schedules: Sports Illustrated, Holiday, Time, Living, True, Redbook; William L. Rech, letters, photos
- Merchandising of Advertising 1961, part 3, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  1961 Advertising and Promotion Schedule, William L. Rech, Advertisement Overview
- Direct Mail Letters by Salesmen, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Mail advertisements, employee introductions, brochures
- True Magazine vs. Newsweek, 1963, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Statistics
- Ocean Press, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Letters, the Ocean Press newspaper of Sept 12 1958
- The News, 1958, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Letters, "Profile of the Millions", statistics
- Beverage Industry News, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Beverage Industry News Nov 1 1957, publishers statement, rate card
- Club Executive, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Letters
- Arizona Beverage Journal, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Letter, magazine advertisement print
- American Home Magazine Advertising, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Letters, statistics
- Modern Bride, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Living Magazine, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Letters, telegram, magazine pages
- Distributor Group Visits, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Taylor Bulletin
- Info Re-Regulations, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Letters, instruction manuals
- Champagne Tax, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Letters, "The Exorbitant Federal Tax on Light Sparkling Wines", "The Present Status of the Champagne Industry", Greyton H. Taylor
- NABCA Reports, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  News bulletin, letters, publications
- State Regulations, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Bulletins, letters, Walter S. Taylor
- Hotel Product News, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Letters, publication
- Holiday Magazine, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Magazine pages, letters, telegrams, Grayton H. Taylor
- Executive Steward Magazine, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Letters, Jack W. Lauts, Grayton H. Taylor, William L. Rech
- Connecticut Liquor Control Commission, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Letters, Grayton H. Taylor
- Buchman and Buchman part 1, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Letters, Henry J. Buchman, Abraham M. Buchman, Walter S. Taylor, State Liquor Authority
- Buchman and Buchman part 2, 1955-1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Letters, State Liquor Authority approved advertising material, images, photos, Grayton H. Taylor
- State of New Hampshire, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Letters, Laws and Regulations published material
- Kansas Approval on Advertising, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Letters, report
- Georgia Advertising Approval, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Letters, advertisement samples, point-of-sale advertising materials, flattened wine box, Grayton H. Taylor
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Oct 1961, October 1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Letters, report, Walter S. Taylor, Grayton H. Taylor, William L. Rech
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Nov 1961, November 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Walter S. Taylor, Grayton H. Taylor, William L. Rech
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Dec 1961, December 1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Jan 1962, January 1962 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Feb 1962, February 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Mar 1962, March 1962 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Apr 1962, April 1962 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, May 1962, May 1962 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, June 1962, June 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, July 1962, July 1962 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Oct 1962, August 1962 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Sept 1962, September 1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Oct 1962, October 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Nov 1961, November 1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Taylor Wine Co. and D'Arcy Advertising Company, Oct 1961, October 1961 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Letters, report, Grayton H. Taylor, William L. Rech
- Marketing Information, 1955-1961 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Magazines, statistics,
- Conference Reports D'Arcy, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- 1962 Conferences with D'Arcy and NSO, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- D'Arcy Advertising Co. Complete Mailing List for Taylor Wine Co., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Letters, mailing list
- National Sales Conference, January 9-11, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Letters, reports, papers
- Reports and Papers on Wine, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Local Advertising, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Cornell, travel guides, articles, Walter S. Taylor
- West Coast Advertising, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Winery - Distributor Advertisements, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Great Western Advertisements, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Control State Advertisements, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Canadian Advertising, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Walter S. Taylor's Advertising Slides, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  slides, negatives
- Taylor Champagne Purse, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Audio recording on magnetic tape
- Magazine Advertisers Coverage Service, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Media Considerations, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Statistics, reports, D'Arcy Advertising Company
- Data on Advertising, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Advertising Schedule Copies, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Bill Kleins Party Book, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  Letters, order reports
- Walter S. Taylor Business and Accounting Coursework (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Worksheets, tests
- Lulumae Gage Accounting Coursework (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Walter S. Taylor English Coursework (Box 2, Folder 37)
  Essays
- Financial Statement and Overview, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Data from studies involving corks with John Barnard, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Wines by Taylor, 1939; V-732 (Box 3)
  Describes the art of wine making in New York State and the Taylor Wine Company. VHS print of original 1939 16mm film. DVD copy available in collection #6695, DVD 169.
- Wines by Taylor, 1939; V-733 (Box 3)
  Betacam SP print of original 1939 16mm film. DVD copy available in collection #6695, DVD 169.
- Savor the flavor, romancing America's grape., 2006; DVD-47 (Box 3)
- D. Bauder mail, 1897-1907 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Wine advertisements and pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Two handkerchiefs with embroidered "S", Undated; MU-1915-1916 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Miscellaneous postcards, 1890-1920 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- F.M. Champlin letters, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Taylor family photos, 1960-1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Additional family photos, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Walter Taylor photos, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Taylor family history items (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Personal correspondence - Lillian, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Personal correspondence - Walter Taylor, 1960's-1970's (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Family correspondence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- General correspondence, 1960-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Greyton H. Taylor wine museum material (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Walter S. Taylor farewell address, 1970-04-23 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Barrell dinner, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Annual industry questionnaire, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- St. Mary's 10th annual wine tasting party, 1986-06-06 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Certificates, 1976, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Grape country calandar, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Living Wine Grapes, by Walter S. Taylor, Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Walter S. Taylor artwork (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Invitation - White House tour, 1972-07-20 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Wine fest flier, 1985-03-16 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Legh T. Knowles, Jr. - celebration party, 1988-10-27 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- News clippings, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Invitation - Glenn Curtiss Day ceremonies, Hammondsport, NY, 1964-06-27 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Invitation - 10th anniversary presidential gala ball, 1989-10-01-1989-10-02 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Space shuttle wine - wine bottle labels, Undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Wine labels, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Press releases, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Unkown nots, Undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Notes on tools, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Publications, 1899, 1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Wine tissue paper, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous items (Box 5, Folder 4)
- NYS Department of State, introduction of Walter S. Taylor prior to South Africa and Australia visit, 1970-02-11 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Wine museum material (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Wine building plans (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Earl aviation prints by H. Hawkins, autographed, Undated (Folder 1)